{
  "theme": [
    {
      "Questions": {
        "theme": [
          {
            "Question": "Which historical drama is based on the reign of Henry VIII?",
            "TrueAnswer": "The Tudors",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Reign",
              "Versailles",
              "Downton Abbey"
            ],
            "Explanation": "'The Tudors' follows the early reign of King Henry VIII of England, showcasing his marriages and political intrigues."
          },
          {
            "Question": "In 'Peaky Blinders', what business does the Shelby family operate?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Betting",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Bootlegging",
              "Textiles",
              "Mining"
            ],
            "Explanation": "The Shelby family runs an illegal betting enterprise in post-World War I Birmingham in the TV series 'Peaky Blinders.'"
          },
          {
            "Question": "Which historical event is depicted in 'Band of Brothers'?",
            "TrueAnswer": "World War II",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "American Civil War",
              "Vietnam War",
              "World War I"
            ],
            "Explanation": "'Band of Brothers' follows the journey of Easy Company, part of the 506th Parachute Infantry Regiment, from D-Day through the end of World War II."
          },
          {
            "Question": "What is the royal house at the center of 'The Crown'?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Windsor",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Tudor",
              "Stuart",
              "Plantagenet"
            ],
            "Explanation": "'The Crown' chronicles the reign of Queen Elizabeth II, a member of the House of Windsor, and significant events from the mid-20th century."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Which historical figure is the main character in 'Marco Polo'?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Kublai Khan",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Julius Caesar",
              "Cleopatra",
              "Napoleon Bonaparte"
            ],
            "Explanation": "'Marco Polo' revolves around the Venetian explorer's interactions with Kublai Khan, the founder of the Yuan dynasty in China."
          },
          {
            "Question": "What era is depicted in 'Peaky Blinders'?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Post-World War I",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Victorian Era",
              "Roaring Twenties",
              "Great Depression"
            ],
            "Explanation": "'Peaky Blinders' showcases the aftermath of World War I, exploring the societal and economic changes in Britain during the 1920s."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Who is the central figure in 'Vikings'?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Ragnar Lothbrok",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "William the Conqueror",
              "Attila the Hun",
              "Genghis Khan"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Ragnar Lothbrok is a legendary Norse hero and the central character of the series, known for his conquests and exploration."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Which historical dynasty is featured in 'The Last Kingdom'?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Saxon",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Carolingian",
              "Merovingian",
              "Hohenstaufen"
            ],
            "Explanation": "'The Last Kingdom' portrays the conflicts between the Saxon kingdoms and the Viking invasions in the late 9th century."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Where does 'The White Queen' take place?",
            "TrueAnswer": "England",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "France",
              "Spain",
              "Italy"
            ],
            "Explanation": "'The White Queen' is set in England during the Wars of the Roses, focusing on the power struggles among the York and Lancaster families."
          },
          {
            "Question": "What historical figure is at the center of 'The Borgias'?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Pope Alexander VI",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Richard the Lionheart",
              "Catherine de' Medici",
              "Ivan the Terrible"
            ],
            "Explanation": "'The Borgias' explores the controversial reign of Rodrigo Borgia, who became Pope Alexander VI during the Renaissance period."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Which historical event is depicted in 'The Great'?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Russian Empress",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "French Revolution",
              "American Civil War",
              "Spanish Inquisition"
            ],
            "Explanation": "The series 'The Great' offers a satirical portrayal of Catherine the Great's rise to power as the Empress of Russia in the 18th century."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Who is the central character in 'Wolf Hall'?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Thomas Cromwell",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Anne Boleyn",
              "Henry VIII",
              "Elizabeth I"
            ],
            "Explanation": "'Wolf Hall' centers on Thomas Cromwell, a key figure in the court of King Henry VIII, focusing on political maneuvering and alliances."
          },
          {
            "Question": "What historical event is the backdrop for 'Jamestown'?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Colonization of Virginia",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Gold Rush in California",
              "French Revolution",
              "Industrial Revolution"
            ],
            "Explanation": "'Jamestown' portrays the early English settlement in the Americas and the challenges faced by the colonists in Virginia during the 17th century."
          },
          {
            "Question": "What historical figure is the main character in 'Medici: Masters of Florence'?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Cosimo de' Medici",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Genghis Khan",
              "Cleopatra",
              "Napoleon Bonaparte"
            ],
            "Explanation": "'Medici: Masters of Florence' centers on Cosimo de' Medici, a prominent figure in the banking and political spheres during the Italian Renaissance."
          },
          {
            "Question": "What historical era does 'The Pillars of the Earth' depict?",
            "TrueAnswer": "12th Century",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "16th Century",
              "18th Century",
              "20th Century"
            ],
            "Explanation": "'The Pillars of the Earth' is set in the 12th century and revolves around the construction of a cathedral and the political intrigue of the time."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Which historical figure is portrayed in 'Rome'?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Julius Caesar",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Alexander the Great",
              "Genghis Khan",
              "Cleopatra"
            ],
            "Explanation": "'Rome' follows the rise of Julius Caesar and the subsequent power struggles in ancient Rome during the last days of the Roman Republic."
          },
          {
            "Question": "What time period does 'Victoria' revolve around?",
            "TrueAnswer": "19th Century",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "18th Century",
              "20th Century",
              "Middle Ages"
            ],
            "Explanation": "'Victoria' focuses on the early reign of Queen Victoria, highlighting her ascension to the throne and the challenges she faced in the 19th century."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Which royal family is at the center of 'The Spanish Princess'?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Tudor",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Habsburg",
              "Bourbon",
              "Romanov"
            ],
            "Explanation": "'The Spanish Princess' delves into the life of Catherine of Aragon, her marriage to Prince Arthur, and her eventual union with King Henry VIII of the Tudor dynasty."
          },
          {
            "Question": "What historical setting is depicted in 'Outlander'?",
            "TrueAnswer": "18th Century Scotland",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Medieval England",
              "Ancient Greece",
              "Wild West"
            ],
            "Explanation": "'Outlander' intertwines historical events with time-travel elements, following the adventures of Claire Randall in 18th century Scotland during the Jacobite uprising."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Who is the famous explorer in 'The Terror: Infamy'?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Captain James Cook",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Vasco da Gama",
              "Ferdinand Magellan",
              "Marco Polo"
            ],
            "Explanation": "'The Terror: Infamy' incorporates supernatural elements within the backdrop of Japanese-American internment during World War II, featuring the historical figure Captain James Cook."
          }
        ]
      }
    }
  ]
}